Rajaneesh Balakrishnan: Hi, welcome to the
community session on introduction to RPA.
My self  Rajaneesh Balakrishnan
I am an UiPath MVP,  certified
advanced RPA developer and
founder of "2AutomateAnything".
This Orientation  session is for
anyone who is interested in RPA.
or currently working in RPA.
This will help you refresh your knowledge
to align with essential RPA concepts.
Let's get started.
Today, we are going to discuss about RPA
in the context of digital transformation
from an enterprise perspective, how
to  define RPA and its characteristics
and benefits, how we can identify
automation  candidate from list of
business processes . RPA in Action.
using a sample business use case, and
finally list of all  our learnings.
I hope you all are ready.
Let's jump in.
Before I start talking anything about RPA.
Let me give you a quick overview
on  Digital transformation, which
is a big thing in today's world.
In simple terms, replacing older
technology with newer Technology  is
called  digital transformation.
In other words, digital transformation.
It is an adoption of digital
technology to transform the services.
or , businesses through replacing
the non-digital or manual processes
with the digital process,.
Automation plays a significant
role in digital transformation.
However, there are many types
of automatio...Robotic process
automation, RPA plays a key role in
driving this digital transformation.
Now let's see what is RPA.
Robotic process automation, RPA.
This can be defined as automation
of work using digital robots.
Please.
Note these robots are not real robots
t or that you see in scifi movies.
These are only for illustration purposes.
To expand it furth r..
It is a technology that allows the
computer software to mimic actions.
Typically perform by human users.
For digital systems to perform
the business processes.
Although robots perform multiple actions,
the key actions that are performed by
these Robots are, that they are able to
capture data from an applications are
from any input, input, data, et cetera.
Uh, it is able to run applications, um,
Based on the user interactions, it is able
to capture and run data on applications.
It is able to trigger responses,
which means like it is able to act
based upon the given inputs, etc.
Able to communicate with
different multiple systems.
And also it is able to communicate
with human users, just for inputs.
Although these robots have
multiple characteristics.
Some distinctive characteristics
are such as they are able to emulate
human actions and these robots can
operate in multiple environments  or
applications that has user interface.
They can perform processes
using structured data format
and these robots, the specific.
use about these robots are
they're able to, uh, the robots
are able to work continuously
and has high degree of accuracy.
Now let us move on to the targeted
processes in any business  environment
settings, just to identify
the key automation candidates.
RPA  depends on certain rules.
Let us see this one  by one, the
first  of all , highly manual.
The process that are highly manual are
the best candidates for automation.
And second.
It's mostly repeatitive . And
time consuming process.
Some processes are repetitive in
nature and also it's highly complex
and it is mostly time consuming.
Next is the rule based.
So by rule based, I mean
the business processes.
Follow your standard structure.
That is the step by step instruction
to execute any business process.
This, this, these processes does
not change frequently and follow the
similar structure on daily basis.
Next is the low exception rate,
which means the system is stable
enough to perform the automation.
And there is not many exceptions are
raised during this business process
execution, and finally, the standard
electronically readable input.
In which the robots are easily able
to read these inputs from any files
or from, multiple applications, the
input  are in a standard readable input.
Now, let us see a  sample business use
case where a retail organization sends
contract to its hundreds of customers.
Uh, it just number repeater
and time consuming.
And this seems to be a
perfect automation candidate.
And let us look more details
into this business processes
and the types of data used.
So I'm just moving to , Uipath
studio X and, uh, uh, corresponding
folders  to deep dive into this.
Let me explain a little bit further that.
So I'm just opening up a
contract of sale template.
So this is the template used
by the business user, just to.
Copy and paste this company
name, the company address,
seller name and seller address.
This is going to be very dynamic and
this total amount is going to come
from sale of goods, uh, Excel data.
And along with that, uh, Sale Item
table and this exchange rates is going
to be highly dynamic on daily basis.
So the robot will.
Open Google to find the
exchange rate for that date.
And it's also going to paste
this logo for the seller and
the buyer along with the date.
So I'm just going to do it for only
one customer, um, considering the time.
And, uh, this robot is able to perform
for such operation for multiple customers.
So I'm just going to show you the
contract for sale of goods, mock data.
So where I have data for only one
customer, when the date is today and
the company name, company, address,
seller name seller address along with
the goods data, uh, which is this table.
So I'm expecting the robot
to copy the entire table and
paste it into that template.
And this total amount also
should be copied to the template.
And similarly for any number of contract
data, the robot will be able to do.
But for this example, I say tool,
I'm going to do it for only one day.
Yeah.
So let me, um, navigate to the studio
X in a high level, there are two steps.
One is to create a new copy from template
and second is to create the report.
So in the carete the report, So you
use the template and perform only
operations that is to copy and paste the
data from Excel to the word template.
And also it opens the, uh, the web
application for the currency conversion
just to, uh, convert the dollar values.
It's just from Euro to a university.
So it, but from all the operations
and everything, uh, we'll be
ready once this run is completed.
So let me,  perform , a quick run on,
on this process and see how it works.
I'm going to click on the Run project.
So you can see the Robot
has started executing.
It has open the contract of sale, the
contract of sale of goods, et cetera.
And the, um,
and  web application  so it's
performing all the operation.
So once all this application
are close, like we can check
how the execution takes place.
I think it has completed
all the operations.
Let me check the output tab so I
can see from the audit, it has used
the word document just to copy the
template, a contract template, and
it has used the Excel file to just
copy the data from Excel to the work.
And also it has used the web publication
just to perform a search for Euro to USD.
And finally it has closed all
the Applications . So Let me
check the contract of sale.
You can see the document is completed now.
So I'm just going to verify this ex
the document, the contract of sale.
So this has been highlighted only for,
uh, this, uh, verification purpose.
So this names has been modified.
Maybe just the buyer name and the
seller name, this seller address, uh,
and the table, this table has come from
the Excel along with just total value.
And the  exchange rate has
been  updated and apparently
the data also has been updated.
And one more update is the seller
logo and Buyer logo has been updated.
So imagine there is a hundreds
of templates like this
business user has to create.
So he no need to do all these repeated
and manual process for the entire day
instead of the robot can help him do this
job so he can focus on better, um, focus
on adding more value to his business
that is contacting the customer and focus
on the customer service perspective.
So ms.
Has, uh, so the robot has done
a very good job of doing this.
Uh, so you can imagine, uh, they can also
do it for hundreds of data and also can
implement sending the email automatically
to the configured customer and reading
the data from a database instead of Excel.
Now, let us discuss the benefits under RPA
provides an unlimited number of benefits.
Let us discuss the top three benefits.
Use RPA in business context.
First of all, it is
not - invasive by non-invasive.
I mean, it does not require any
IT Architecture change or deep
integration with underlying systems.
It provides fast, Reliable and cost
effective solutions for lightweight
integration into processes or IT assets.
Second, it is easy to scale the amount
of work  involved entirely  depends on
the process, uh, as change is expected to
happen frequently in the business context.
Um, so if an  RPA  solution is
used, the business can either
scale up or scale down the RPA
solutions based on the requirements.
Finally, it's future proof of technology
robots work with today's technology.
If the.
Technology changes in future the
robot  are yet Extensible . So it
can be able to adapt to the latest
technology and deliver to automate
the latest available technologies.
And that takes us to
this end of this session.
Uh, so in this demo, because
seeing what is RPA, what is
this digital transformation,
the RPA actions and benefits.
Uh, selecting the RPA business candidates
and finally we saw  a demo run.
And so using a sample business use case,
I hope you are, all enjoyed this session.
Um, and I wish you all the
best in your RPA learnings.
Let me know if you have any
questions or clarifications and
please connect me in LinkedIn.
And, uh, know your comments,
uh, I hope to meet you all in
another session soon until then.
Thank you very much.